Inventory of the Hart Collection 1762-1913
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Hart Collection 1762-1913
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2008.112
1.00
Hart, John, 1860-1937; Beverley, Martha A.; Cullen, John; Holt, George Edmund; Jesse, Julie; Leigh, John T.; Lyle, James A.; Smith, Richard C.; Wilson, J. arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 00/00/1935.
Biographical Note
John Hart was an educator having served on the faculty of Virginia Polytechnic Institute (Virginia Tech) and as a book dealer in Richmond, Virginia. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/John Hart.
Scope and Contents
Autographs albums, library catalogs of personal libraries, maps, math notes and scrapbooks.Many collections and material were purchased from John Hart during the 1930's and filed under their own accession numbers or even interfiled with existing collections.
Arrangement of Materials
Grouped by type of material.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Knights of the Golden Horseshoe
Genre/Form of Material:
Autograph albums; Catalogs; Daybooks; Maps.; Photographs
Occupation:
Physicians--Virginia--Richmond.
Topical Term:
Flags--Confederate States of America; Libraries, Private.; Library catalogs.; Medical practice--Virginia--History.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Autograph Albums, id35337
  - id65657 (Box 1)
    - Martha A. Beverly Autograph Album, id35338 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Julie Jesse Autograph Album, 1858-1865; id35339 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Autograph book of Richard C. Smith, 1861-1867; id35340 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Daybook of John Cullen, id35341
  - id65659 (Box 1)
    - Daybook of John Cullen, 1841-1842; id35342 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Library Catalogs, id35343
  - id65660 (Box 1)
    - Library Catalog – J. Wilson, undated; id35344 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Library Catalog - Virginia, id35345 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Maps, id35346
  - id65661 (Box 1)
    - Maps, id35347 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Map of Route of Gov. Spottswood, 1716; id35348 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Math Notebook, id35349
  - id65663 (Box 1)
    - Math notebook of John T. Leigh, 1860; id35350 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photograph, id35351
  - id65665 (Box 1)
    - Photograph of Giant’s Causeway in Aberdeen, Scotland., id35352 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Scrapbooks, id35354
  - id65666 (Box 2)
    - Scrapbook of George Edmund Holt, 1908-1913; id35355 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook - James A. Lyle, of Bel Air, Maryland., Undated; id35356 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook - Monograms, id35357 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook - Maine, 1835-1877; id35358 (Box 2, Folder 4)